[
    {
        "question": "1. What do you understand by workflow in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Workflow in Salesforce allows you to automate standard internal procedures and processes for saving time across your organization. It helps to evaluate records as they are created or updated and determines if an automated action needs to occur.\nAutomation functions in Salesforce include the functions such as sending follow-up emails, tracking the customer map journey, performing other marketing activities to boost the sales of the company, etc.\nA workflow rule is a major container for a set of workflow instructions. These instructions are usually summed up in an if/then statement. Workflow rules are divided into two main components. They are:\nCriteria: The “if” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what must be true of the record for the workflow rule to execute the related actions.\nActions: The “then” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what to do when the record meets the criteria.\nConsider an example for a workflow, “if it is raining, then bring an umbrella”. In this example, the criteria are “it is raining” and the action is “bring an umbrella”. If the criteria aren’t met, then the action isn’t executed. The workflow rule’s actions are executed only when a record meets all the criteria of a workflow rule. Workflow in Salesforce allows you to automate standard internal procedures and processes for saving time across your organization. It helps to evaluate records as they are created or updated and determines if an automated action needs to occur. Automation functions in Salesforce include the functions such as sending follow-up emails, tracking the customer map journey, performing other marketing activities to boost the sales of the company, etc. A workflow rule is a major container for a set of workflow instructions. These instructions are usually summed up in an if/then statement. Workflow rules are divided into two main components. They are:\nCriteria: The “if” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what must be true of the record for the workflow rule to execute the related actions.\nActions: The “then” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what to do when the record meets the criteria. Criteria: The “if” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what must be true of the record for the workflow rule to execute the related actions.\nActions: The “then” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what to do when the record meets the criteria. Criteria: The “if” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what must be true of the record for the workflow rule to execute the related actions. Actions: The “then” part of the “if/then” statement i.e., what to do when the record meets the criteria. Consider an example for a workflow, “if it is raining, then bring an umbrella”. In this example, the criteria are “it is raining” and the action is “bring an umbrella”. If the criteria aren’t met, then the action isn’t executed. The workflow rule’s actions are executed only when a record meets all the criteria of a workflow rule. Workflow In Salesforce  Workflow In Salesforce",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is an object in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "In Salesforce, objects are database tables that are used to store the data of an organization. There are two types of objects in Salesforce. They are: Standard object: These are the objects provided by the Salesforce platform, which includes contacts, accounts, cases, campaigns, opportunities, leads, products, contracts, reports, dashboards, etc.\nCustom object: They are objects created by developers based on the business process. It stores the important and unique information of an organization. It gives a structure for data sharing. The custom object includes page layouts, custom fields, relationship to other objects, custom user interface tab, etc. Standard object: These are the objects provided by the Salesforce platform, which includes contacts, accounts, cases, campaigns, opportunities, leads, products, contracts, reports, dashboards, etc. Custom object: They are objects created by developers based on the business process. It stores the important and unique information of an organization. It gives a structure for data sharing. The custom object includes page layouts, custom fields, relationship to other objects, custom user interface tab, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is meant by an App in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "An App in Salesforce is a logical container that holds various details related to the company such as a logo, name, business operations, etc. You can customize apps to match your needs, or you can develop new applications by combining custom and standard tabs. The process to create an app in Salesforce is given below: Setup —> build—> Create—> App—> Click on new. By following the above procedure, you can develop an application as you want.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Explain different types of apps we can use in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "There are two types of apps that we can create in Salesforce. They are: Custom app: They are mainly used by business owners who want to build an app that suits their business requirements from time to time. It’s widely used in the market.\nConsole app: It can be used only in the client service business, where we focus on tackling the client’s issues. Compared to a custom app it’s not widely used in the market. Custom app: They are mainly used by business owners who want to build an app that suits their business requirements from time to time. It’s widely used in the market. Console app: It can be used only in the client service business, where we focus on tackling the client’s issues. Compared to a custom app it’s not widely used in the market.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is sharing rule?",
        "answer": "Sharing rules are applied when a user wishes to permit access to other users like public groups, roles, or territories. It gives greater access to particular users by making automatic exceptions to your organization-wide sharing settings. You can define total sharing rules up to 300 for a particular object, including criteria-based or guest user sharing rules up to 50, if available for the object.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is an Audit trail in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "An Audit trail in Salesforce is a unique feature that helps in tracking the changes made in the organization by you and other administrators. In that way, you will always get to know who has modified the project at the last minute. It is helpful for the organization with more administrators. By using an audit trail, you can get to know the details about changes made, the date and time of the change, and the username of the team member who made the changes.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is the difference between role and profile?",
        "answer": "The main difference between role and profile is given below - Role Profile\nThe role helps in defining data visibility for a particular user. A profile sets the limitation for what an user can do in the organization.\nBased on the hierarchy, a role defines which user data a user can see. Profile defines permissions\nDefining role to a user is not mandatory Defining profile is mandatory\nRoles provide a feature to control access to records by impacting reports. For example,“My Teams” filter. Roles function if a security model (OWDs) of an organization is set to private. Profiles help to decide record privileges i.e. assuming the user can observe the record, it concludes what the user can function, edit, delete, view on that record. It controls other system privileges like export data, mass email, etc. Role Profile\nThe role helps in defining data visibility for a particular user. A profile sets the limitation for what an user can do in the organization.\nBased on the hierarchy, a role defines which user data a user can see. Profile defines permissions\nDefining role to a user is not mandatory Defining profile is mandatory\nRoles provide a feature to control access to records by impacting reports. For example,“My Teams” filter. Roles function if a security model (OWDs) of an organization is set to private. Profiles help to decide record privileges i.e. assuming the user can observe the record, it concludes what the user can function, edit, delete, view on that record. It controls other system privileges like export data, mass email, etc. Role Profile Role Profile Role Profile The role helps in defining data visibility for a particular user. A profile sets the limitation for what an user can do in the organization.\nBased on the hierarchy, a role defines which user data a user can see. Profile defines permissions\nDefining role to a user is not mandatory Defining profile is mandatory\nRoles provide a feature to control access to records by impacting reports. For example,“My Teams” filter. Roles function if a security model (OWDs) of an organization is set to private. Profiles help to decide record privileges i.e. assuming the user can observe the record, it concludes what the user can function, edit, delete, view on that record. It controls other system privileges like export data, mass email, etc. The role helps in defining data visibility for a particular user. A profile sets the limitation for what an user can do in the organization. The role helps in defining data visibility for a particular user. A profile sets the limitation for what an user can do in the organization. Based on the hierarchy, a role defines which user data a user can see. Profile defines permissions Based on the hierarchy, a role defines which user data a user can see. Profile defines permissions Defining role to a user is not mandatory Defining profile is mandatory Defining role to a user is not mandatory Defining profile is mandatory Roles provide a feature to control access to records by impacting reports. For example,“My Teams” filter. Roles function if a security model (OWDs) of an organization is set to private. Profiles help to decide record privileges i.e. assuming the user can observe the record, it concludes what the user can function, edit, delete, view on that record. It controls other system privileges like export data, mass email, etc. Roles provide a feature to control access to records by impacting reports. For example,“My Teams” filter. Roles function if a security model (OWDs) of an organization is set to private. Profiles help to decide record privileges i.e. assuming the user can observe the record, it concludes what the user can function, edit, delete, view on that record. It controls other system privileges like export data, mass email, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is a profile in Salesforce? Can two users have the same profile?",
        "answer": "The profile in Salesforce is defined as a collection of settings and permissions that define what a user can do in Salesforce. So it gives you the authority to access certain records in Salesforce. There are multiple profiles available in Salesforce. For example, a sales profile can have access to leads, contacts, campaigns, opportunities, etc. The people who work under one department may be assigned the same profiles. Consider the case of sales profile, many people work under it and each person who works under this is assigned with the same profile. Hence we can say that any number of people can have the same profile.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is a Master–Detail relationship in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Master-Detail relationship is a relationship between a parent and child where the master represents the parent and the detail represents a child. This relationship can be used when we want to control the display of detail records based on the value present in the master record.\nThe master object completely takes control of the behavior of the Detail object. The survival of the child is dependent on the parent, because if the parent gets deleted then the child automatically gets deleted. You can create Roll-up summary fields in master records which will calculate the SUM, AVG, and MIN of the child records.\nConsider an example of a courier company model, where a delivery schedule is always linked to a delivery location. If we delete a delivery location from our list, then all the related delivery schedules should also be removed. Such a dependency can be achieved only through a Master-Detail relationship. Master-Detail relationship is a relationship between a parent and child where the master represents the parent and the detail represents a child. This relationship can be used when we want to control the display of detail records based on the value present in the master record. The master object completely takes control of the behavior of the Detail object. The survival of the child is dependent on the parent, because if the parent gets deleted then the child automatically gets deleted. You can create Roll-up summary fields in master records which will calculate the SUM, AVG, and MIN of the child records. Consider an example of a courier company model, where a delivery schedule is always linked to a delivery location. If we delete a delivery location from our list, then all the related delivery schedules should also be removed. Such a dependency can be achieved only through a Master-Detail relationship.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is dashboard in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "A dashboard in Salesforce is a pictorial representation of the report. It displays data from source reports as visual components. These components provide a snapshot of key metrics and performance indicators of the organization at a single glance. A single dashboard is capable of displaying 20 reports at a time.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are the features of Salesforce",
        "answer": "Contact management Contact management It provides easier contact management by giving access to critical data of the customers and interaction history.\nIt gives complete customer details including insights and engage-enhancement strategies. Social data of the customers can be used for a deeper understanding of their particular behavior regarding any product or service. It provides easier contact management by giving access to critical data of the customers and interaction history. It gives complete customer details including insights and engage-enhancement strategies. Social data of the customers can be used for a deeper understanding of their particular behavior regarding any product or service. Opportunity management Opportunity management Salesforce provides an opportunity to view the activity timeline of your customers. It represents different stages of a particular deal which helps you to decide your next move.\nYou can see critical details of the activity timeline in addition to the business competitors. The readymade templates ensure hassle-free emailing to the clients. Salesforce provides an opportunity to view the activity timeline of your customers. It represents different stages of a particular deal which helps you to decide your next move. You can see critical details of the activity timeline in addition to the business competitors. The readymade templates ensure hassle-free emailing to the clients. Quote management Quote management Quote management of the products will have tracking of the products, which are part of your deal and it includes the standard price, product code, quantity, and quoted price. Also, you can establish quantity along with revenue schedule and it reflects the delivery terms and payment.\nSalesforce CRM app is having a built-in quoting mechanism that automatically quotes client data. It also creates an approved template PDF and sends it directly to the customer as an email. Quote management of the products will have tracking of the products, which are part of your deal and it includes the standard price, product code, quantity, and quoted price. Also, you can establish quantity along with revenue schedule and it reflects the delivery terms and payment. Salesforce CRM app is having a built-in quoting mechanism that automatically quotes client data. It also creates an approved template PDF and sends it directly to the customer as an email. Lead management Lead management Lead management is featured with an affluent activity timeline. It provides an access to up-to-date contacts on the timeline. Also, it makes use of the sales paths to understand the related documents.\nCRM app functions as a fast lead converter machine, which informs you about the original source of the leads. Automatic emailing boosts your revenue-generating mechanism. Lead management is featured with an affluent activity timeline. It provides an access to up-to-date contacts on the timeline. Also, it makes use of the sales paths to understand the related documents. CRM app functions as a fast lead converter machine, which informs you about the original source of the leads. Automatic emailing boosts your revenue-generating mechanism. Sales data Sales data Using Salesforce CRM you can get the right sales data at the right time. It provides a faster connection with key decision-makers.\nYou can easily plan territories. It can be used for increasing sales and marketing productivity with the latest and most accurate data. Using Salesforce CRM you can get the right sales data at the right time. It provides a faster connection with key decision-makers. You can easily plan territories. It can be used for increasing sales and marketing productivity with the latest and most accurate data. Mobility Mobility The Salesforce mobile app turns your mobile device into a portable sales office by allowing the users to access CRM data at any time and from anywhere.\nYou can log calls, work opportunities, check dashboards, respond to hot leads, etc. The Salesforce mobile app turns your mobile device into a portable sales office by allowing the users to access CRM data at any time and from anywhere. You can log calls, work opportunities, check dashboards, respond to hot leads, etc. Workflow and approvals Workflow and approvals It allows to use of visual workflow to rapidly design and automate any of the business processes with drag and drop simplicity. And you can successfully manage flexible approvals processes for deal discounts, expenses, and more. It allows to use of visual workflow to rapidly design and automate any of the business processes with drag and drop simplicity. And you can successfully manage flexible approvals processes for deal discounts, expenses, and more. File sync and share File sync and share It’s easier to share files, discuss them, publish the best and track your content in real-time by using Salesforce.\nYou can quickly find what you are looking for, share it securely, and also subscribe to receive alerts when something changes. It’s easier to share files, discuss them, publish the best and track your content in real-time by using Salesforce. You can quickly find what you are looking for, share it securely, and also subscribe to receive alerts when something changes. Dynamic dashboards and custom reports Dynamic dashboards and custom reports Dashboards offer a real-time picture of how your business is performing in the market. Users can recognize market trends, calculate the activities and clear up the quantities. You can build your own dashboard by using drag and drop icons in Salesforce CRM.\nIt allows creating your own customized sales forecasting report with Salesforce CRM. By using a simple drag and drop feature, users are able to adjust the fields and view data with filters. Charts provide real-time data to give you the latest insight. Dashboards offer a real-time picture of how your business is performing in the market. Users can recognize market trends, calculate the activities and clear up the quantities. You can build your own dashboard by using drag and drop icons in Salesforce CRM. It allows creating your own customized sales forecasting report with Salesforce CRM. By using a simple drag and drop feature, users are able to adjust the fields and view data with filters. Charts provide real-time data to give you the latest insight. Sales forecasting Sales forecasting It tracks the journey of the leads in the pipeline to look into whether they are reaching their destination i.e. deals or not. It gives brilliant forecasting on sales upon analyzing the same. You can apply your right judgment to the forecasted amount and according to that, you can plan your strategies.\nYou can make use of in-line editing, multicurrency support, override visibility, etc. to stay on top of your business.\nIt gives the right credit to the right person and permits them to see the forecast as per overlays. It tracks the journey of the leads in the pipeline to look into whether they are reaching their destination i.e. deals or not. It gives brilliant forecasting on sales upon analyzing the same. You can apply your right judgment to the forecasted amount and according to that, you can plan your strategies. You can make use of in-line editing, multicurrency support, override visibility, etc. to stay on top of your business. It gives the right credit to the right person and permits them to see the forecast as per overlays.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What are the benefits of using Salesforce CRM?",
        "answer": "The benefits of using Salesforce CRM is given below: Communicate using automation tools: With the help of Salesforce Einstein Bots, its features can automatically respond to chats on time. Thus avoids giving delayed response.\nData syncing from different applications: Data from other applications such as MailChimp and G Suite can be integrated into the Salesforce platform. This removes the difficulty of moving from one software to another. Using Salesforce mobile app, you can keep track of your data anytime and anywhere.\nUtilization of data analytics tools: Salesforce’s Einstein Analytics gives insights so that users can address the changing data right away. Salesforce has a collection of reporting tools and dashboards that will help you collect information and work on it properly.\nFollowing customer activity: It helps to understand the customer’s journey through the sales cloud so that you will have easier access to their behavior and background. You can review the click rates on your email campaigns to help you recognize what works best for your customers.\nAssisting customers through chat: A chat box is provided by the service cloud’s live agent depending on the interaction of your customers or followers on your web page. By connecting with the customer profile, your service team can deliver answers. This is helpful in improving customer experiences by letting agents respond quickly.\nUsing an omnichannel feature: Multi-channel feature provided by the service cloud automatically shifts conversations from various channels directly to the agents. This gives them one place to connect with customers through calls, social media, chat, messaging, or email.\nConsistent engagement with current customers: Looking for a new customer is more expensive than keeping the current ones. Use the gathered data in Salesforce’s CRM to create consistent marketing campaigns.\nYou can build apps: Force.com, a Platform as a Service(PaaS) simplifies customizing and building apps for any device without using a complicated infrastructure. Communicate using automation tools: With the help of Salesforce Einstein Bots, its features can automatically respond to chats on time. Thus avoids giving delayed response. Data syncing from different applications: Data from other applications such as MailChimp and G Suite can be integrated into the Salesforce platform. This removes the difficulty of moving from one software to another. Using Salesforce mobile app, you can keep track of your data anytime and anywhere. Utilization of data analytics tools: Salesforce’s Einstein Analytics gives insights so that users can address the changing data right away. Salesforce has a collection of reporting tools and dashboards that will help you collect information and work on it properly. Following customer activity: It helps to understand the customer’s journey through the sales cloud so that you will have easier access to their behavior and background. You can review the click rates on your email campaigns to help you recognize what works best for your customers. Assisting customers through chat: A chat box is provided by the service cloud’s live agent depending on the interaction of your customers or followers on your web page. By connecting with the customer profile, your service team can deliver answers. This is helpful in improving customer experiences by letting agents respond quickly. Using an omnichannel feature: Multi-channel feature provided by the service cloud automatically shifts conversations from various channels directly to the agents. This gives them one place to connect with customers through calls, social media, chat, messaging, or email. Consistent engagement with current customers: Looking for a new customer is more expensive than keeping the current ones. Use the gathered data in Salesforce’s CRM to create consistent marketing campaigns. You can build apps: Force.com, a Platform as a Service(PaaS) simplifies customizing and building apps for any device without using a complicated infrastructure.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What is trigger in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "The trigger is defined as an Apex code that executes to perform custom actions, before or after modifications like insert, update, delete, etc. that has done to records in Salesforce. Triggers can be defined for top-level standard objects, like contact or account, custom objects, and few standard child objects. They are active by default when created. When the specified database events occur, Salesforce automatically fires active triggers. The syntax for creating a trigger is given below: trigger TriggerName on ObjectName (trigger_events)\n{\n   code_block\n} trigger TriggerName on ObjectName (trigger_events)\n{\n   code_block\n} To execute a trigger before or after insert, update, delete and undelete operations, specify multiple trigger events like before insert, before delete, after insert, after update etc. in a comma-separated list. Trigger in Salesforce  Trigger in Salesforce",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is the difference between static and dynamic dashboards in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Static dashboards Dynamic dashboards\nThese are the default dashboards that are visible to any user Dynamic dashboards show data tailored for a specific user\nIt is used to show organizational-wide data to a set of users It is used to show a single user’s specific data, such as the number of sales closed, leads converted, etc\nIt can be scheduled to automatically refresh its data We can’t schedule dynamic dashboard because when the dashboard is opened by us, it will display the real-time generated data Static dashboards Dynamic dashboards\nThese are the default dashboards that are visible to any user Dynamic dashboards show data tailored for a specific user\nIt is used to show organizational-wide data to a set of users It is used to show a single user’s specific data, such as the number of sales closed, leads converted, etc\nIt can be scheduled to automatically refresh its data We can’t schedule dynamic dashboard because when the dashboard is opened by us, it will display the real-time generated data Static dashboards Dynamic dashboards Static dashboards Dynamic dashboards Static dashboards Dynamic dashboards These are the default dashboards that are visible to any user Dynamic dashboards show data tailored for a specific user\nIt is used to show organizational-wide data to a set of users It is used to show a single user’s specific data, such as the number of sales closed, leads converted, etc\nIt can be scheduled to automatically refresh its data We can’t schedule dynamic dashboard because when the dashboard is opened by us, it will display the real-time generated data These are the default dashboards that are visible to any user Dynamic dashboards show data tailored for a specific user These are the default dashboards that are visible to any user Dynamic dashboards show data tailored for a specific user It is used to show organizational-wide data to a set of users It is used to show a single user’s specific data, such as the number of sales closed, leads converted, etc It is used to show organizational-wide data to a set of users It is used to show a single user’s specific data, such as the number of sales closed, leads converted, etc It can be scheduled to automatically refresh its data We can’t schedule dynamic dashboard because when the dashboard is opened by us, it will display the real-time generated data It can be scheduled to automatically refresh its data We can’t schedule dynamic dashboard because when the dashboard is opened by us, it will display the real-time generated data",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is Apex in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Apex is a strongly typed and object-oriented programming language that permits developers to execute flow and transaction control statements on Salesforce platform servers in conjunction with calls to the API. It uses syntax that looks similar to Java and pretends like database stored procedures.\nApex allows developers to add business logic to many system events, including Visualforce pages, button clicks, and related record updates. This code can be initiated by requests from web services and from triggers on objects.\nAll Apex code runs completely on-demand on the Lightning platform. Apex code is written and saved to the platform by developers. Through the user interface, end-users trigger the execution of Apex code. Apex is a strongly typed and object-oriented programming language that permits developers to execute flow and transaction control statements on Salesforce platform servers in conjunction with calls to the API. It uses syntax that looks similar to Java and pretends like database stored procedures. Apex allows developers to add business logic to many system events, including Visualforce pages, button clicks, and related record updates. This code can be initiated by requests from web services and from triggers on objects. All Apex code runs completely on-demand on the Lightning platform. Apex code is written and saved to the platform by developers. Through the user interface, end-users trigger the execution of Apex code.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Explain different components of dashboard available in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "Some of Salesforce dashboard components are explained below: Gauge: It is used for displaying a single value within a custom value range.\nMetric: This is used for showing a single pair of key–values. We can enter the metric label directly on the components by clicking the empty text field next to the grand total. All metrics placed in the dashboard column would be displayed as a single component.\nTable: Tables are used for showing report data in the form of lists. For example, top five or bottom five opportunities.\nVisualforce page: It is used for forming a custom component as a dashboard or displaying information that is not available in other component types.\nCharts: It is used for showing comparisons. Charts are divided into 6 types. They are line Chart, vertical bar chart, horizontal bar chart, donut, pie, and funnel. Gauge: It is used for displaying a single value within a custom value range. Gauge: Metric: This is used for showing a single pair of key–values. We can enter the metric label directly on the components by clicking the empty text field next to the grand total. All metrics placed in the dashboard column would be displayed as a single component. Metric: Table: Tables are used for showing report data in the form of lists. For example, top five or bottom five opportunities. Table: Visualforce page: It is used for forming a custom component as a dashboard or displaying information that is not available in other component types. Visualforce page: Charts: It is used for showing comparisons. Charts are divided into 6 types. They are line Chart, vertical bar chart, horizontal bar chart, donut, pie, and funnel. Charts:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are Governor limits in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Governor limits control how much data a shared database can store. They help to make sure that no one monopolizes the shared resources like storage, CPU, and memory. Whenever the Apex code exceeds the limit, it issues a runtime exception that cannot be handled.\nThe following list gives some of the governor limits in Salesforce:\nPush notification limits\nPer-Transaction Apex limits\nSize-Specific Apex limits\nMiscellaneous Apex limits\nStatic Apex limits\nEmail limits\nExamples of governor limits in Salesforce:\nThe total number of sendEmail methods permitted is 10.\nThe total number of records retrieved by a SOQL query is 50,000.\nMaximum CPU time on the Salesforce servers is 10,000ms on synchronous Apex.\nThe total number of callouts(web services calls or HTTP requests) in a transaction is 100. Governor limits control how much data a shared database can store. They help to make sure that no one monopolizes the shared resources like storage, CPU, and memory. Whenever the Apex code exceeds the limit, it issues a runtime exception that cannot be handled. The following list gives some of the governor limits in Salesforce:\nPush notification limits\nPer-Transaction Apex limits\nSize-Specific Apex limits\nMiscellaneous Apex limits\nStatic Apex limits\nEmail limits Push notification limits\nPer-Transaction Apex limits\nSize-Specific Apex limits\nMiscellaneous Apex limits\nStatic Apex limits\nEmail limits Push notification limits Per-Transaction Apex limits Size-Specific Apex limits Miscellaneous Apex limits Static Apex limits Email limits Examples of governor limits in Salesforce:\nThe total number of sendEmail methods permitted is 10.\nThe total number of records retrieved by a SOQL query is 50,000.\nMaximum CPU time on the Salesforce servers is 10,000ms on synchronous Apex.\nThe total number of callouts(web services calls or HTTP requests) in a transaction is 100. The total number of sendEmail methods permitted is 10.\nThe total number of records retrieved by a SOQL query is 50,000.\nMaximum CPU time on the Salesforce servers is 10,000ms on synchronous Apex.\nThe total number of callouts(web services calls or HTTP requests) in a transaction is 100. The total number of sendEmail methods permitted is 10. The total number of records retrieved by a SOQL query is 50,000. Maximum CPU time on the Salesforce servers is 10,000ms on synchronous Apex. The total number of callouts(web services calls or HTTP requests) in a transaction is 100.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is junction object in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Junction objects are useful in building many-to-many relationships between objects in Salesforce. Consider an example of recruiting application, where a position for a job is linked to many candidates or a candidate can apply for many other jobs. Here, a third-party object “job application” is referred to as a junction object in order to connect the data model. In the above-given example, “job application” is the junction object. Junction Object in Salesforce  Junction Object in Salesforce",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are Permission sets?",
        "answer": "A Permission Set is a collection of settings or permissions that is used to give access to numerous tools and functions for the user. You can use permission sets for different types of users to extend functional access without changing their profiles. Instead of creating a separate profile each time, you could easily create a Permission Set.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the different types of reports available in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Reports will give a clear picture to the management. Management will make use of reports to track progress towards its various goals, increase revenue, and control expenditure. Reports will also help to predict trends and thus gives the advantage of the increase in profits. There are four types of reports in Salesforce. They are as follows: Matrix report\nA report is formed by grouping the records by rows as well as columns. It is used when you want to see data by two separate dimensions that aren’t related, such as date and product.\nExample: Summarize opportunities by account horizontally and by month vertically.\nSummary report\nA report that provides a listing of data with groupings and subtotals. It is used when subtotals are needed, based on the value of a particular field, or when you want to create a hierarchically grouped report.\nExample: All opportunities for your team subtotaled by owner and sales stage.\nTabular report\nA report that provides details of a company in tabular format. It is used when you want a simple list or an item list with a grand total.\nExample: These reports are used to list all accounts, list of opportunities, list of contacts, etc.\nJoined report\nA report that is created by the mixture of any combination of reports. Like matrix report plus summary report can give you a joined report. Also, matrix reports and tabular reports can give a joined report.\nExample: You can develop a report to display opportunity, case, and activity data for your accounts. Matrix report\nA report is formed by grouping the records by rows as well as columns. It is used when you want to see data by two separate dimensions that aren’t related, such as date and product.\nExample: Summarize opportunities by account horizontally and by month vertically. Matrix report A report is formed by grouping the records by rows as well as columns. It is used when you want to see data by two separate dimensions that aren’t related, such as date and product.\nExample: Summarize opportunities by account horizontally and by month vertically. A report is formed by grouping the records by rows as well as columns. It is used when you want to see data by two separate dimensions that aren’t related, such as date and product. Example: Summarize opportunities by account horizontally and by month vertically. Summary report\nA report that provides a listing of data with groupings and subtotals. It is used when subtotals are needed, based on the value of a particular field, or when you want to create a hierarchically grouped report.\nExample: All opportunities for your team subtotaled by owner and sales stage. Summary report A report that provides a listing of data with groupings and subtotals. It is used when subtotals are needed, based on the value of a particular field, or when you want to create a hierarchically grouped report.\nExample: All opportunities for your team subtotaled by owner and sales stage. A report that provides a listing of data with groupings and subtotals. It is used when subtotals are needed, based on the value of a particular field, or when you want to create a hierarchically grouped report. Example: All opportunities for your team subtotaled by owner and sales stage. Tabular report\nA report that provides details of a company in tabular format. It is used when you want a simple list or an item list with a grand total.\nExample: These reports are used to list all accounts, list of opportunities, list of contacts, etc. Tabular report A report that provides details of a company in tabular format. It is used when you want a simple list or an item list with a grand total.\nExample: These reports are used to list all accounts, list of opportunities, list of contacts, etc. A report that provides details of a company in tabular format. It is used when you want a simple list or an item list with a grand total. Example: These reports are used to list all accounts, list of opportunities, list of contacts, etc. Joined report\nA report that is created by the mixture of any combination of reports. Like matrix report plus summary report can give you a joined report. Also, matrix reports and tabular reports can give a joined report.\nExample: You can develop a report to display opportunity, case, and activity data for your accounts. Joined report A report that is created by the mixture of any combination of reports. Like matrix report plus summary report can give you a joined report. Also, matrix reports and tabular reports can give a joined report.\nExample: You can develop a report to display opportunity, case, and activity data for your accounts. A report that is created by the mixture of any combination of reports. Like matrix report plus summary report can give you a joined report. Also, matrix reports and tabular reports can give a joined report. Example: You can develop a report to display opportunity, case, and activity data for your accounts. Reports Available in Salesforce  Reports Available in Salesforce",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Explain the Force.com platform",
        "answer": "Force.com is the entire framework and codebase on which the whole Salesforce application exists. We can also say that Salesforce is built on Force.com, which is a Platform as a Service (PaaS) that allows us to simplify the design, development, and deployment of cloud-based applications and websites. Developers can work with Cloud Integrated Development Environment (Cloud IDE) and deploy the applications on the servers of Force.com.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are validation rules in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Validation rules in Salesforce consist of a formula or expressions that evaluate the data in one or more fields in a record to meet the standards you specify before the user can save the record. It returns a “True” or “False” value based on the evaluation of the data. Validation rules are responsible for displaying an error message to the user when the condition is “True” due to an invalid value.\nValidation rules are helpful in enforcing integrity constraints against the data. Here we give conditions in the formula editor. If one validation rule fails, Salesforce proceeds to check another validation rule held within the field or record and shows an appropriate error message at that particular field or above the record.\nYou are allowed to create validation rules for fields, objects, campaign members, or case milestones. For example, we can create a validation rule that fires when a user tries to save an account with the incorrect length for the account number. Validation rules in Salesforce consist of a formula or expressions that evaluate the data in one or more fields in a record to meet the standards you specify before the user can save the record. It returns a “True” or “False” value based on the evaluation of the data. Validation rules are responsible for displaying an error message to the user when the condition is “True” due to an invalid value. Validation rules are helpful in enforcing integrity constraints against the data. Here we give conditions in the formula editor. If one validation rule fails, Salesforce proceeds to check another validation rule held within the field or record and shows an appropriate error message at that particular field or above the record. You are allowed to create validation rules for fields, objects, campaign members, or case milestones. For example, we can create a validation rule that fires when a user tries to save an account with the incorrect length for the account number.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What causes data loss in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "There are many things that cause data loss in Salesforce. They are: Human error: Human error: When editing an object definition (incorrectly changing a picklist), importing data (overwriting good data with bad), or merging households are the common situations where human error may occur.\nFor example, when you import data, it becomes important to match up fields. Situations like moving to percent, number, and money from other data types or changing text area to URL, email, phone or text, etc. will lead to incorrect match in fields. If you are updating a large number of records and match up incorrect fields, your records will be invalid. When editing an object definition (incorrectly changing a picklist), importing data (overwriting good data with bad), or merging households are the common situations where human error may occur. For example, when you import data, it becomes important to match up fields. Situations like moving to percent, number, and money from other data types or changing text area to URL, email, phone or text, etc. will lead to incorrect match in fields. If you are updating a large number of records and match up incorrect fields, your records will be invalid. Accidental deletion of Salesforce data: Accidental deletion of Salesforce data: A record (or multiple records) might be accidentally deleted by users or employees. Deleting records could be because of miscommunication, forgetting to remove a contact from being deleted, and many other reasons. So proper training and having a trusted backup/recovery solution are much important. A record (or multiple records) might be accidentally deleted by users or employees. Deleting records could be because of miscommunication, forgetting to remove a contact from being deleted, and many other reasons. So proper training and having a trusted backup/recovery solution are much important. Purposeful deletion of Salesforce data: Purposeful deletion of Salesforce data: Disgruntled employees like the person who has recently got a very bad performance review and thinks their job is at stake or who is jealous of other employees might try to delete the data. A few clicks on the delete button may lead to the deletion of multiple records from Salesforce.\nIf they empty their recycle bin, that data recovery will be difficult using the Weekly Export. It can cause numerous damages if these records are not backed up properly. Disgruntled employees like the person who has recently got a very bad performance review and thinks their job is at stake or who is jealous of other employees might try to delete the data. A few clicks on the delete button may lead to the deletion of multiple records from Salesforce. If they empty their recycle bin, that data recovery will be difficult using the Weekly Export. It can cause numerous damages if these records are not backed up properly. Data sync errors: Data sync errors: If you have more than one admin or use Outlook for Salesforce, you might experience a data sync error at some point.\nFor example, one admin is trying to refresh a sandbox while another admin is working from home and trying to edit an object type in that same sandbox. When this happens, the admin who was editing the object can lose his work in progress.\nContacts in Outlook can over-write good Salesforce data when using Outlook for Salesforce, introducing errors through inappropriate sync. If you have more than one admin or use Outlook for Salesforce, you might experience a data sync error at some point. For example, one admin is trying to refresh a sandbox while another admin is working from home and trying to edit an object type in that same sandbox. When this happens, the admin who was editing the object can lose his work in progress. Contacts in Outlook can over-write good Salesforce data when using Outlook for Salesforce, introducing errors through inappropriate sync.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is Visualforce in Force.com?",
        "answer": "Visualforce can be defined as the UI for the Force.com platform that allows developers to build sophisticated, custom user interfaces which can be hosted natively on the Lightning platform.\nThis Visualforce framework includes a tag-based markup language, a set of server-side “standard controllers” that forms basic database operations(such as queries and saves) and each Visualforce tag corresponds to a user interface components such as a field, section of a page, or a related list, etc.\nIt works on the standard MVC model. It can have strong integration with the database and deploy auto-generated controllers for database objects. The behavior of Visualforce components can be controlled by the developer, by utilizing the same logic that was used in standard Salesforce pages. It is also possible for a developer to associate their own logic with a controller class written in Apex code. Visualforce can be defined as the UI for the Force.com platform that allows developers to build sophisticated, custom user interfaces which can be hosted natively on the Lightning platform. This Visualforce framework includes a tag-based markup language, a set of server-side “standard controllers” that forms basic database operations(such as queries and saves) and each Visualforce tag corresponds to a user interface components such as a field, section of a page, or a related list, etc. It works on the standard MVC model. It can have strong integration with the database and deploy auto-generated controllers for database objects. The behavior of Visualforce components can be controlled by the developer, by utilizing the same logic that was used in standard Salesforce pages. It is also possible for a developer to associate their own logic with a controller class written in Apex code.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What are the differences between trigger and workflow in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Workflow Trigger\nWorkflow is an automated process that fires an action depending on evaluation criteria and rule criteria A trigger is a piece of program code that will be executed before or after a record has been inserted or updated\nWe cannot carry out DML operations on workflow  We can use 20 DML operations in a single trigger\nWe are able to obtain a workflow across the object We are able to access the trigger across the object and associated with that objects\nWe cannot query from database in workflow We can use 20 SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) from the database in a single trigger Workflow Trigger\nWorkflow is an automated process that fires an action depending on evaluation criteria and rule criteria A trigger is a piece of program code that will be executed before or after a record has been inserted or updated\nWe cannot carry out DML operations on workflow  We can use 20 DML operations in a single trigger\nWe are able to obtain a workflow across the object We are able to access the trigger across the object and associated with that objects\nWe cannot query from database in workflow We can use 20 SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) from the database in a single trigger Workflow Trigger Workflow Trigger Workflow Trigger Workflow is an automated process that fires an action depending on evaluation criteria and rule criteria A trigger is a piece of program code that will be executed before or after a record has been inserted or updated\nWe cannot carry out DML operations on workflow  We can use 20 DML operations in a single trigger\nWe are able to obtain a workflow across the object We are able to access the trigger across the object and associated with that objects\nWe cannot query from database in workflow We can use 20 SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) from the database in a single trigger Workflow is an automated process that fires an action depending on evaluation criteria and rule criteria A trigger is a piece of program code that will be executed before or after a record has been inserted or updated Workflow is an automated process that fires an action depending on evaluation criteria and rule criteria A trigger is a piece of program code that will be executed before or after a record has been inserted or updated We cannot carry out DML operations on workflow  We can use 20 DML operations in a single trigger We cannot carry out DML operations on workflow We can use 20 DML operations in a single trigger We are able to obtain a workflow across the object We are able to access the trigger across the object and associated with that objects We are able to obtain a workflow across the object We are able to access the trigger across the object and associated with that objects We cannot query from database in workflow We can use 20 SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) from the database in a single trigger We cannot query from database in workflow We can use 20 SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) from the database in a single trigger",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are record types in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce record types permit us to associate different business processes and display different picklist values and page layouts to different users based on the user profile.\nAdministrators are having the ability to associate record types with the user profiles so that, in the record’s detail page, different users will be able to see different picklist values and page layouts.\nFor example, consider a case where record types are most often used i.e., to create two different sales processes on the Opportunity object. Each of them with different sales stages and page layouts. This will indicate that with record types you will be able to apply multiple page layouts per object as well as per user profile.\nBenefits of record types:\nIt modifies user interaction experience to specific needs of the business.\nAllows for administration in a simple manner as there are fewer fields to maintain. Salesforce record types permit us to associate different business processes and display different picklist values and page layouts to different users based on the user profile. Administrators are having the ability to associate record types with the user profiles so that, in the record’s detail page, different users will be able to see different picklist values and page layouts. For example, consider a case where record types are most often used i.e., to create two different sales processes on the Opportunity object. Each of them with different sales stages and page layouts. This will indicate that with record types you will be able to apply multiple page layouts per object as well as per user profile. Benefits of record types:\nIt modifies user interaction experience to specific needs of the business.\nAllows for administration in a simple manner as there are fewer fields to maintain. It modifies user interaction experience to specific needs of the business.\nAllows for administration in a simple manner as there are fewer fields to maintain. It modifies user interaction experience to specific needs of the business. Allows for administration in a simple manner as there are fewer fields to maintain.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What are page layouts related to Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Page layouts are used to control the layout and organization of buttons, fields, Visualforce, custom links, s-controls, and related lists on object record pages.\nThey are helpful in organizing user interface pages by determining which fields, related lists, and custom links are required, read-only, and visible for the user.\nWe can create many page layouts and apply them to different user groups, with the aim of creating a customized experience. For example, you could have a single account record like ACME Corp., but it displays different information depending on your user profile.\nHere, you can only apply the one-page layout to a single group of users per object, per record type. For example, if you have one record type based on the Accounts object, you can apply only one-page layout per profile. Page layouts are used to control the layout and organization of buttons, fields, Visualforce, custom links, s-controls, and related lists on object record pages. They are helpful in organizing user interface pages by determining which fields, related lists, and custom links are required, read-only, and visible for the user. We can create many page layouts and apply them to different user groups, with the aim of creating a customized experience. For example, you could have a single account record like ACME Corp., but it displays different information depending on your user profile. Here, you can only apply the one-page layout to a single group of users per object, per record type. For example, if you have one record type based on the Accounts object, you can apply only one-page layout per profile.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What are the two types of triggers in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Below are the two types of Apex triggers in Salesforce: Before triggers: It can be used to update or validate record values before it is saved to the database. Before triggers: trigger TriggerName on ObjectName(before event) //Here event can be insert, update or delete\n{\n    code_block\n} trigger TriggerName on ObjectName(before event) //Here event can be insert, update or delete\n{\n    code_block\n} After triggers: It can be used to access field values of the records that are set by the system (such as record’s ID or LastModifiedDate field) that are stored in the database and use this field value to do the changes in other records. Records that fire after the triggers are read-only. After triggers: trigger TriggerName on ObjectName(after event) //Here event can be insert, update or delete\n{\n    code_block\n} trigger TriggerName on ObjectName(after event) //Here event can be insert, update or delete\n{\n    code_block\n}",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What is fiscal year or economical year in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "The fiscal year or economical year is defined as the period of time used for calculating annual financial statements based on starting and ending date of a company’s financial year. In this period of time, whatever the amount of business that Salesforce has done can be considered as fiscal year and depicts the Salesforce revenue. There are two types of fiscal years in Salesforce. They are: Normal or standard fiscal year: It is a period that allows estimating by following the Gregorian calendar year that has a 12-month structure. Starting of the fiscal year can begin with the very first day of any month you choose belonging to a particular year. For example, for the fiscal year starting in April, the standard fiscal year is used.\nCustom fiscal year: It is mainly defined for the companies that lay their forecast based on weekly or quarterly financial planning and can also customize the same. For example, you may have 4 quarters with 13 weeks per quarter in a 4-4-5 pattern or 13 periods per year. Normal or standard fiscal year: It is a period that allows estimating by following the Gregorian calendar year that has a 12-month structure. Starting of the fiscal year can begin with the very first day of any month you choose belonging to a particular year. For example, for the fiscal year starting in April, the standard fiscal year is used. Normal or standard fiscal year: Custom fiscal year: It is mainly defined for the companies that lay their forecast based on weekly or quarterly financial planning and can also customize the same. For example, you may have 4 quarters with 13 weeks per quarter in a 4-4-5 pattern or 13 periods per year. Custom fiscal year:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Explain skinny table. What are the considerations for skinny table?",
        "answer": "Skinny tables in Salesforce are useful in accessing the fields which are frequently used and to avoid joins. This can improve the performance of certain read-only operations such as reports, list views, etc. Skinny tables are highly effective because skinny tables will be in sync with source tables even when the source tables are modified. You need to contact Salesforce customer support if you want to use skinny tables. You cannot create, access, or modify skinny tables yourself. For example, you need to contact Salesforce to update your skinny table definition if you want to add new fields. Considerations for skinny tables are: Considerations for skinny tables are: It can contain an utmost of 100 columns.\nIt cannot hold fields from other objects.\nFor full sandboxes, these skinny tables are copied to your full sandbox organizations. For other types of sandboxes, skinny tables are not copied into your sandbox organizations. To have production skinny tables to be activated, contact Salesforce customer support. It can contain an utmost of 100 columns. It cannot hold fields from other objects. For full sandboxes, these skinny tables are copied to your full sandbox organizations. For other types of sandboxes, skinny tables are not copied into your sandbox organizations. To have production skinny tables to be activated, contact Salesforce customer support. The below figure displays an Account view, a corresponding database table along with a skinny table that can speed up account queries. Skinny Table  Skinny Table",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Explain the types of SOQL statements in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "Salesforce Object Query Language(SOQL) is useful in querying the records from database.com depending on the requirement. There are 2 types of SOQL statements: Static SOQL and Dynamic SOQL. database.com Static SOQL: Static SOQL: The Static SOQL statement is written using [] (array brackets). This statement is similar to IINQ (Ion Integrated Query).\nIt is used in the condition where you don’t have any dynamic changes in the SOQL query. We don’t use Static SOQL when the field name or where the condition is needed to be dynamically defined. The Static SOQL statement is written using [] (array brackets). This statement is similar to IINQ (Ion Integrated Query). It is used in the condition where you don’t have any dynamic changes in the SOQL query. We don’t use Static SOQL when the field name or where the condition is needed to be dynamically defined. Example for Static SOQL query: Example for Static SOQL query: Contact[] contacts = [SELECT testfield__C, FirstName, LastName FROM Contact WHERE LastName = 'Dhanya']; Contact[] contacts = [SELECT testfield__C, FirstName, LastName FROM Contact WHERE LastName = 'Dhanya']; Dynamic SOQL: Dynamic SOQL: It is used to refer to the SOQL string creation at run time with Apex code.\nDynamic SOQL allows you to create more flexible applications. For example, you are able to create a search based on end-user input or update records with different field names.\nTo create a Dynamic SOQL query at run time using a Database.query() method, in any one of the given below ways:\nReturn a single sObject when the single record is returned by a query.\nsObjects s = Database.query(string_limit_1);\nReturn a list of sObjects when more than a single record is returned by a query.\nList<sObject> sobjList = Database.query(string); It is used to refer to the SOQL string creation at run time with Apex code. Dynamic SOQL allows you to create more flexible applications. For example, you are able to create a search based on end-user input or update records with different field names. To create a Dynamic SOQL query at run time using a Database.query() method, in any one of the given below ways:\nReturn a single sObject when the single record is returned by a query.\nsObjects s = Database.query(string_limit_1);\nReturn a list of sObjects when more than a single record is returned by a query.\nList<sObject> sobjList = Database.query(string); Return a single sObject when the single record is returned by a query.\nsObjects s = Database.query(string_limit_1);\nReturn a list of sObjects when more than a single record is returned by a query.\nList<sObject> sobjList = Database.query(string); Return a single sObject when the single record is returned by a query.\nsObjects s = Database.query(string_limit_1);  sObjects s = Database.query(string_limit_1); Return a list of sObjects when more than a single record is returned by a query.\nList<sObject> sobjList = Database.query(string);  List<sObject> sobjList = Database.query(string); Example for Dynamic SOQL query: Example for Dynamic SOQL query: String myTestString = 'TestName';\nList<sObject> sobjList = Database.query('SELECT Id FROM MyCustomObject__c WHERE Name = :myTestString'); String myTestString = 'TestName';\nList<sObject> sobjList = Database.query('SELECT Id FROM MyCustomObject__c WHERE Name = :myTestString');",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are the different types of email templates available in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "The list of different types of email templates that can be created in Salesforce is given below: Text: All the users in the organization are allowed to create or change these templates.\nHTML with letterhead: Only administrators and users with the “Edit HTML Templates” permissions are able to create these templates based on a letterhead. The look and feel of your HTML email templates are defined by the letterheads. It can inherit the logo, text, and color settings from a letterhead.\nCustom HTML: It is an extension of HTML with a letterhead. Administrators and users having “Edit HTML Templates” permissions can create custom HTML templates without using the letterhead. You must have knowledge about HTML or get the HTML code to insert it into your email template.\nVisualforce: Administrators and developers are allowed to create these templates by using Visualforce. Visualforce templates provide advanced functionalities like merging with a recipient’s data, where the content of a template can have data from multiple records. Text: All the users in the organization are allowed to create or change these templates. Text: HTML with letterhead: Only administrators and users with the “Edit HTML Templates” permissions are able to create these templates based on a letterhead. The look and feel of your HTML email templates are defined by the letterheads. It can inherit the logo, text, and color settings from a letterhead. HTML with letterhead: Custom HTML: It is an extension of HTML with a letterhead. Administrators and users having “Edit HTML Templates” permissions can create custom HTML templates without using the letterhead. You must have knowledge about HTML or get the HTML code to insert it into your email template. Custom HTML: Visualforce: Administrators and developers are allowed to create these templates by using Visualforce. Visualforce templates provide advanced functionalities like merging with a recipient’s data, where the content of a template can have data from multiple records. Visualforce:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What is Salesforce lightning?",
        "answer": "Salesforce lightning is a component-based framework for application development, which has a collection of tools and technologies that aim to effectively increment the performance of the Salesforce platform. These tools include an entirely new version of a framework, visual upgrades, new and optimized interfaces, and more. It is designed to simplify processes for business users, who do not have any programming experience. Salesforce lightning Salesforce lightning  Using the lightning platform we can easily create apps that solve business problems and provide engaging experiences. Few lightning features are: Few lightning features are: Lightning app builder: It provides drag and drop capacities to facilitate the creation of an application and customization.\nLightning component framework: It consists of tools and extensions that allow the development of reusable components and standalone applications along with customization of the Salesforce mobile app.\nAppExchange for components: It makes over 50 partner components present in the app builder.\nDesign system: It provides style guides and user experience practices for application development.\nLightning Connect: It is an integration tool that makes it easier for applications of Force.com to consume data from an external source that meets the OData specification. Lightning app builder: It provides drag and drop capacities to facilitate the creation of an application and customization. Lightning component framework: It consists of tools and extensions that allow the development of reusable components and standalone applications along with customization of the Salesforce mobile app. AppExchange for components: It makes over 50 partner components present in the app builder. Design system: It provides style guides and user experience practices for application development. Lightning Connect: It is an integration tool that makes it easier for applications of Force.com to consume data from an external source that meets the OData specification.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Can you give an example of a Salesforce API and its usage?",
        "answer": "Salesforce provides a variety of APIs that allows developers to interact with the system in many ways. They are: REST: REST: By using REST API you can easily integrate with Salesforce applications using simple HTTP methods in either XML or JSON formats. It is an ideal API for developing mobile applications or external clients.\nConsider an example of retrieving information about the Salesforce version. You need to submit a request for the Versions resource by using the following code: By using REST API you can easily integrate with Salesforce applications using simple HTTP methods in either XML or JSON formats. It is an ideal API for developing mobile applications or external clients. Consider an example of retrieving information about the Salesforce version. You need to submit a request for the Versions resource by using the following code: curl https://yourInstance.salesforce.com/services/data/ curl https://yourInstance.salesforce.com/services/data/ You have to replace the “your instance” text with the instance for your organization.\nThe output from this request is as follows. You have to replace the “your instance” text with the instance for your organization.\nThe output from this request is as follows.  [\n    {\n        \"label\" : \"Winter '12\",\n        \"url\" : \"/services/data/v23.0\",\n        \"version\" : \"23.0\"\n    }\n    ...\n] [\n    {\n        \"label\" : \"Winter '12\",\n        \"url\" : \"/services/data/v23.0\",\n        \"version\" : \"23.0\"\n    }\n    ...\n] Bulk: The Bulk API provides programmatic access that lets you quickly load and query a huge amount of data into your Salesforce organization. Bulk: Streaming: The Streaming API can be used to trigger and receive notifications, whenever changes to Salesforce data are made according to the defined SOQL query criteria. It is useful when you want notifications to be pushed from the server to the client based on your defined criteria. Streaming: Conclusion Salesforce is playing a vital role in any company’s sales and marketing automation activities. The demand for qualified Salesforce professionals has seen its peak in recent days. Moreover, competition is also becoming tough for Salesforce-related positions, so preparation is inevitable if you want to shine out of the crowd. Salesforce is increasingly used as a term synonymous with CRM. Organizations can utilize Salesforce for varied applications like Contact Management, Workflow Creation, Customer Engagement, Opportunity Tracking, Task Management, and many more. In addition, you can also collaborate with your colleagues, run analytics, and access Salesforce from a mobile dashboard. Additional Resources Salesforce Architecture – Detailed Explanation\nSalesforce Admin Interview Questions and Answers\nSalesforce Lightning Interview Questions and Answers\nSalesforce LWC Interview Questions\nTechnical Interview Questions Salesforce Architecture – Detailed Explanation Salesforce Architecture – Detailed Explanation Salesforce Admin Interview Questions and Answers Salesforce Admin Interview Questions and Answers Salesforce Lightning Interview Questions and Answers Salesforce Lightning Interview Questions and Answers Salesforce LWC Interview Questions Salesforce LWC Interview Questions Technical Interview Questions Technical Interview Questions",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are the differences between SOQL and SOSL in salesforce?",
        "answer": "SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) SOSL(Salesforce Object Search Language)\nUsing SOQL we can search only one object at a time Using SOSL we can search multiple objects at a time\nWe can query on all fields of any of the datatype  We can query on the fields whose data type is phone, text, and email\nDML operations can be performed on query results DML operations cannot be performed on search results\nIndexing happens synchronously Indexing happens asynchronously\nWe can use SOQL in the classes and triggers SOSL cannot be used in triggers but can be used in classes SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) SOSL(Salesforce Object Search Language)\nUsing SOQL we can search only one object at a time Using SOSL we can search multiple objects at a time\nWe can query on all fields of any of the datatype  We can query on the fields whose data type is phone, text, and email\nDML operations can be performed on query results DML operations cannot be performed on search results\nIndexing happens synchronously Indexing happens asynchronously\nWe can use SOQL in the classes and triggers SOSL cannot be used in triggers but can be used in classes SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) SOSL(Salesforce Object Search Language) SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) SOSL(Salesforce Object Search Language) SOQL(Salesforce Object Query Language) SOSL(Salesforce Object Search Language) Using SOQL we can search only one object at a time Using SOSL we can search multiple objects at a time\nWe can query on all fields of any of the datatype  We can query on the fields whose data type is phone, text, and email\nDML operations can be performed on query results DML operations cannot be performed on search results\nIndexing happens synchronously Indexing happens asynchronously\nWe can use SOQL in the classes and triggers SOSL cannot be used in triggers but can be used in classes Using SOQL we can search only one object at a time Using SOSL we can search multiple objects at a time Using SOQL we can search only one object at a time Using SOSL we can search multiple objects at a time We can query on all fields of any of the datatype  We can query on the fields whose data type is phone, text, and email We can query on all fields of any of the datatype We can query on the fields whose data type is phone, text, and email DML operations can be performed on query results DML operations cannot be performed on search results DML operations can be performed on query results DML operations cannot be performed on search results Indexing happens synchronously Indexing happens asynchronously Indexing happens synchronously Indexing happens asynchronously We can use SOQL in the classes and triggers SOSL cannot be used in triggers but can be used in classes We can use SOQL in the classes and triggers SOSL cannot be used in triggers but can be used in classes",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What do you mean by a sandbox in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "A sandbox is a copy of the production environment/ organization and it is used for the purpose of testing and development. It’s very useful because sandboxes are completely isolated from your Salesforce production organization, so it allows you to test out new ideas on the duplicate database without disturbing the original production environment. You can use the sandbox whenever you want to test a newly formed Force.com application or Visualforce page. Instead of testing it directly in production, you can develop and test it in the sandbox organization. Using this, you can develop the application without any difficulty and then migrate the metadata and data to the production environment. Doing this in a non-production environment permits developers to freely test and experiment with the newly created applications. There are four types of sandboxes in Salesforce: Developer sandbox: Developer sandbox: It is a copy of the production organization, it copies all the information of an application and configuration to the sandbox. It is mainly used for the development and testing task in an isolated environment.\nThis type of sandboxes has limitations of up to 200MB of test or sample data. You can refresh a developer sandbox once a day. It is a copy of the production organization, it copies all the information of an application and configuration to the sandbox. It is mainly used for the development and testing task in an isolated environment. This type of sandboxes has limitations of up to 200MB of test or sample data. You can refresh a developer sandbox once a day. Developer pro sandbox: Developer pro sandbox: It copies all of your organization’s reports, dashboards, apps, price books, products, and customizations under setup. But it excludes all of your organization’s custom and standard object records, attachments, and documents.\nThis type of sandboxes has limitations of up to 1GB of test or sample data. We can refresh developer pro sandboxes once a day. It copies all of your organization’s reports, dashboards, apps, price books, products, and customizations under setup. But it excludes all of your organization’s custom and standard object records, attachments, and documents. This type of sandboxes has limitations of up to 1GB of test or sample data. We can refresh developer pro sandboxes once a day. Partial data sandbox: Partial data sandbox: A partial data sandbox is a developer sandbox plus the data you define in a sandbox template, which is intended to be used only as a testing environment. It includes the reports, dashboards, price books, applications, products, and customizations under the setup (including all of your metadata).\nAdditionally, these sandboxes can have your organization’s custom and standard object records, documents, and attachments up to 5 GB of data along with a maximum of 10,000 records per chosen object.\nA partial data sandbox is smaller compared to a full sandbox and has a shorter refresh interval. You can refresh partial data sandboxes every 5 days.\nSandbox templates permit you to select specific data and objects to copy to your sandbox, thus you can control the size as well as the content of each sandbox. Sandbox templates are available only for partial data or full sandboxes. A partial data sandbox is a developer sandbox plus the data you define in a sandbox template, which is intended to be used only as a testing environment. It includes the reports, dashboards, price books, applications, products, and customizations under the setup (including all of your metadata). Additionally, these sandboxes can have your organization’s custom and standard object records, documents, and attachments up to 5 GB of data along with a maximum of 10,000 records per chosen object. A partial data sandbox is smaller compared to a full sandbox and has a shorter refresh interval. You can refresh partial data sandboxes every 5 days. Sandbox templates permit you to select specific data and objects to copy to your sandbox, thus you can control the size as well as the content of each sandbox. Sandbox templates are available only for partial data or full sandboxes. Full sandbox: Full sandbox: It is a replica of production including custom and standard object records, attachments, and documents and is used only as a testing environment.\nYou can refresh full copy sandboxes every 29 days. It is a replica of production including custom and standard object records, attachments, and documents and is used only as a testing environment. You can refresh full copy sandboxes every 29 days. Sandbox in Salesforce  Sandbox in Salesforce",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Explain the various types of object relationships in Salesforce.",
        "answer": "An object relationship in Salesforce can be defined as a two-way link or association between two or more objects. Relationships are created by generating custom relationship fields on an object. Due to this, whenever a user views the records, they are also able to see and access related data. The various types of object relationships in Salesforce are: Master-Detail relationship (1:n): Master-Detail relationship (1:n): It is a parent-child relationship where the master object controls the behavior of dependent detail and sub-detail object. It is a 1:n relationship, in which there is only one parent, but multiple children.\nThe master field cannot be empty, since it is the controlling object. If a master object’s record or field gets deleted, the corresponding record or fields in the dependent object will also be deleted. This is called a cascade delete. Child object fields will inherit the owner, sharing, and security settings from the parent object. You can create Master-Detail relationships between two custom objects, or between a standard object and custom object until the standard object remains as a master in the relationship.\nFor example, you can define a Master-Detail relationship with two objects such as Account—Expense report. It expands the relationship to sub detail records, such as Account—Expense report—Expense line item. You will be then allowed to perform operations across the master—detail—sub detail relationship. It is a parent-child relationship where the master object controls the behavior of dependent detail and sub-detail object. It is a 1:n relationship, in which there is only one parent, but multiple children. The master field cannot be empty, since it is the controlling object. If a master object’s record or field gets deleted, the corresponding record or fields in the dependent object will also be deleted. This is called a cascade delete. Child object fields will inherit the owner, sharing, and security settings from the parent object. You can create Master-Detail relationships between two custom objects, or between a standard object and custom object until the standard object remains as a master in the relationship. For example, you can define a Master-Detail relationship with two objects such as Account—Expense report. It expands the relationship to sub detail records, such as Account—Expense report—Expense line item. You will be then allowed to perform operations across the master—detail—sub detail relationship. Lookup relationship (1:n): Lookup relationship (1:n): These relationships are useful for creating a link between two objects, without the dependency on the parent object. This is again a form of parent-child relationship where there is only a single parent, but multiple children exist (1:n relationship).\nDespite master being the controlling field, deleting a master record will not automatically delete the lookup field in the child object. So the records in the child object will not get affected and there will not be any cascade delete here. Child fields will not inherit the owner, sharing, or security settings of its parent.\nWith a lookup relationship, you are permitted to link two different objects or link an object with itself (except for the user object). For example, you may want to link a custom object “Bug” with itself for showing how two different bugs are related to the same problem. These relationships are useful for creating a link between two objects, without the dependency on the parent object. This is again a form of parent-child relationship where there is only a single parent, but multiple children exist (1:n relationship). Despite master being the controlling field, deleting a master record will not automatically delete the lookup field in the child object. So the records in the child object will not get affected and there will not be any cascade delete here. Child fields will not inherit the owner, sharing, or security settings of its parent. With a lookup relationship, you are permitted to link two different objects or link an object with itself (except for the user object). For example, you may want to link a custom object “Bug” with itself for showing how two different bugs are related to the same problem. Junction relationship (Many-To-Many): Junction relationship (Many-To-Many): You can use this kind of relationship whenever you want to create two Master-Detail relationships. By linking 3 custom objects, we can create two Master-Detail relationships. In this, two objects will be represented as master objects and the third object will act as a dependent on both of them. In simpler words, we can say that there will be a child object for both master objects.\nThis relationship allows every record of one object to be linked with several records of another object and vice versa. For example, you can create a custom object “Bug” that relates to a standard object in such a way that a bug can be related to multiple causes, and also a single case can be related to multiple bugs. You can use this kind of relationship whenever you want to create two Master-Detail relationships. By linking 3 custom objects, we can create two Master-Detail relationships. In this, two objects will be represented as master objects and the third object will act as a dependent on both of them. In simpler words, we can say that there will be a child object for both master objects. This relationship allows every record of one object to be linked with several records of another object and vice versa. For example, you can create a custom object “Bug” that relates to a standard object in such a way that a bug can be related to multiple causes, and also a single case can be related to multiple bugs. Hierarchical relationship: Hierarchical relationship: This is a special lookup relationship, that is available only for the user object.\nIt allows users to use a lookup field to associate a single user with another user that does not refer to itself in a direct or indirect way. For example, to store the direct manager of each user, you are allowed to create a custom hierarchical relationship field. This is a special lookup relationship, that is available only for the user object. It allows users to use a lookup field to associate a single user with another user that does not refer to itself in a direct or indirect way. For example, to store the direct manager of each user, you are allowed to create a custom hierarchical relationship field. External lookup relationship: External lookup relationship: This relationship links a child's standard, custom, or external object to a master external object.\nIn this relationship, the standard External ID field values on the parent external object are matched against the external lookup relationship field values of the child object. This relationship links a child's standard, custom, or external object to a master external object. In this relationship, the standard External ID field values on the parent external object are matched against the external lookup relationship field values of the child object. Indirect lookup relationship: Indirect lookup relationship: This relationship links a child's external object to a master standard or custom object.\nFor matching and associating the records, you will mention the parent object field and the child object field when you create an indirect lookup relationship field on an external object. Here, you have to select the parent object’s custom unique, external ID field to match against the child object’s indirect lookup relationship field. This relationship links a child's external object to a master standard or custom object. For matching and associating the records, you will mention the parent object field and the child object field when you create an indirect lookup relationship field on an external object. Here, you have to select the parent object’s custom unique, external ID field to match against the child object’s indirect lookup relationship field. Relationships in Salesforce  Relationships in Salesforce",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. How many ways we can share a record?",
        "answer": "With the help of the given below methods we can share records in Salesforce: Role hierarchy: Role hierarchy: Whenever a user is added to a role, the user above the current user in the hierarchy of roles will have access to reading the records and inheriting the permissions.\nFollow the steps for role hierarchy: Go to Setup → find manage users' → roles → set up roles → click on ‘add role’ → provide name and click on save. Whenever a user is added to a role, the user above the current user in the hierarchy of roles will have access to reading the records and inheriting the permissions. Follow the steps for role hierarchy: Go to Setup → find manage users' → roles → set up roles → click on ‘add role’ → provide name and click on save. OWD: OWD: OWD(Organization-Wide Defaults) allows you to give permissions to the organization-wide and to define baseline setting for the organization. It is also helpful in defining the user’s accessibility level to the user where a user can see other user’s records.\nOWD settings can be Public Read Only, Private, Public Read, and Write.\nFollow the steps for OWD: Go to Setup → find the Security Controls → click on ‘sharing settings’ → click on ‘Edit. OWD(Organization-Wide Defaults) allows you to give permissions to the organization-wide and to define baseline setting for the organization. It is also helpful in defining the user’s accessibility level to the user where a user can see other user’s records. OWD settings can be Public Read Only, Private, Public Read, and Write. Follow the steps for OWD: Go to Setup → find the Security Controls → click on ‘sharing settings’ → click on ‘Edit. Manual sharing: Manual sharing: Manual sharing is sharing a single record/file to a single user or group of users through manual access.\nWe can see a button for manual sharing on the detail page of the record and it can be seen only when the OWD setting is private. Manual sharing is sharing a single record/file to a single user or group of users through manual access. We can see a button for manual sharing on the detail page of the record and it can be seen only when the OWD setting is private. Criteria based sharing rules: Criteria based sharing rules: If we want to share records based on conditions such as share records with a group of users with the criteria of the country is India.\nFollow the steps for criteria-based sharing rules: Go to Setup → security controls → sharing settings → select the object and provide name and conditions then click on save. If we want to share records based on conditions such as share records with a group of users with the criteria of the country is India. Follow the steps for criteria-based sharing rules: Go to Setup → security controls → sharing settings → select the object and provide name and conditions then click on save. Apex sharing: Apex sharing: Sharing object is available for each and every object in Salesforce. For example, the Account object’s share object is AccountShare.\nBy using Apex, if we want to share the records then we have to create a record to the shared object. Sharing object is available for each and every object in Salesforce. For example, the Account object’s share object is AccountShare. By using Apex, if we want to share the records then we have to create a record to the shared object.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is a wrapper class in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "A wrapper class is a type of container class, which contains a group of objects as its members. It is of an abstract data type. We use a wrapper class for enclosing the collected data. A wrapper class is defined by a programmer, that acts as custom objects, along with wrapper class properties. The instances of a wrapper class are helpful in displaying various objects in the corresponding table on a Visualforce page. Some of the main advantages of using wrapper class by developers in Salesforce are given below: The wrapper class structure is as efficient as that of a good data visualization process for a web page, especially in the case where the developers are dealing with the JSON structure.\nThe developers are not required to manage the passing of any map structure in order to browse necessary elements. Moreover, usage of wrapper class by developers will lead to ease the process of managing relationships between different objects.\nWrapper class usage prevents any penalty faced by the users for passing an object of Salesforce. Also, it makes the respective object extendable to constructors of a class.\nThe use of the wrapper class supports the developers for efficiently organizing the concerned data, provided the data is properly nested. The wrapper class structure is as efficient as that of a good data visualization process for a web page, especially in the case where the developers are dealing with the JSON structure. The developers are not required to manage the passing of any map structure in order to browse necessary elements. Moreover, usage of wrapper class by developers will lead to ease the process of managing relationships between different objects. Wrapper class usage prevents any penalty faced by the users for passing an object of Salesforce. Also, it makes the respective object extendable to constructors of a class. The use of the wrapper class supports the developers for efficiently organizing the concerned data, provided the data is properly nested.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. What is Future annotation(@future)?",
        "answer": "Future annotations are used to specify methods that are executed asynchronously.\nMethods having future annotation must be static methods and can only return a void type. The arguments specified must be primitive data types or arrays of primitive data types or collections of primitive data types. These methods cannot take sObjects or objects as parameters.\nWhen you specify a method with @future annotation, it will be executed only when Salesforce has available resources.\nFor example, you can use future annotation while making an asynchronous web service callout to an external service. Whereas without the usage of future annotation, web service callout will be created from the same thread which is executing the Apex code, and no additional processing will take place until that callout is complete (synchronous processing). Future annotations are used to specify methods that are executed asynchronously. Methods having future annotation must be static methods and can only return a void type. The arguments specified must be primitive data types or arrays of primitive data types or collections of primitive data types. These methods cannot take sObjects or objects as parameters. When you specify a method with @future annotation, it will be executed only when Salesforce has available resources. For example, you can use future annotation while making an asynchronous web service callout to an external service. Whereas without the usage of future annotation, web service callout will be created from the same thread which is executing the Apex code, and no additional processing will take place until that callout is complete (synchronous processing). Syntax: Syntax: global class class_name\n{\n    @future\n    Static void methodname(parameters)\n    {\n        //body of the method\n    }\n}` global class class_name\n{\n    @future\n    Static void methodname(parameters)\n    {\n        //body of the method\n    }\n}`",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce is a cloud-based service. It is a customer relationship management (CRM) platform. Salesforce is a software as a Service (SaaS). It helps you to manage customer relationships, integrate with other systems, and build apps. The tool helps you to manage and create a custom solution as per your business requirement.\n\nBefore Salesforce, companies had their servers for customer relationship management (CRM). They were costly and time taking. They were very hard to use. Feasible solution to this problem is to build an affordable CRM software and delivering it entirely online as a service.\nIn a few years, there has been a significant surge in cloud computing technologies. Salesforce has an immense impact on the world of computing. Salesforce is developed as the fifth largest software company in the world. It is the top CRM service provider.\nADVERTISEMENT",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What is an app in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "An app is a collection of tabs that works as a unit to provide functionality. Users can switch between apps in force.com app's drop-down menu.\nA Salesforce application is a container of tabs, processes, and services.\nWe can create new apps by grouping some standard app, customize existing apps according to our work.\nSalesforce provides many standard apps such as call center, marketing, sales, etc.\nThere are two types of Salesforce application:\nADVERTISEMENT\nADVERTISEMENT\nCustom App\nService cloud control\nSalesforce create application\nADVERTISEMENT\nFollow the below steps to create a Salesforce app:\nStep1: Follow this navigation: Setup-> AppSetup-> create-> apps-> click on 'new'\nStep2: Select custom application radio button-> provide the app name\nStep3: Click on the next button\nStep4: Select the image from the document object\nStep5: Select the objects\nStep6: Click on the visible checkbox and save\nTo add this Salesforce app to any other profiles or tabs. Follow the below steps\nStep1: Setup-> Appsetup-> create-> apps->\nStep2: Select the app from the list and click on edit\nStep3: If we want to change the image, then click on insert an image and take the image from documents.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What are objects in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Objects are the database tables in Salesforce. Objects allow storing data specific to the organization in Salesforce.\n\nThere are two types of objects in Salesforce:\nStandard objects\nCustom objects\nStandard objects\nStandard objects are such objects that are inbuilt in Salesforce.com.\nExample: accounts, contacts, products, leads, opportunities, campaigns, users, contracts, Report, and dashboards, etc.\nCustom objects\nCustom objects are such objects that are created by us. These objects are user-defined objects. Custom objects store information which is important and unique to our organization.\n\nCustom objects are an integral part of any application. They provide a structure for sharing data.\nCustom objects hold the following properties.\nCustom fields\nRelationship to other objects\nPage layouts\nA custom user interface tab",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What are user profiles in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "User profiles are a group of permissions and settings which provide lightning access to a user. Salesforce admins can assign the users with a profile depending upon their job roles. The user profile includes all the tabs, records, and page access that user require.\nYou can set up and manage the profile by which you can conventionally create a secure boundary that dictates user's access rights.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) Can we assign the same profile to two different users? Is it possible that two profiles can be assigned to the same user?",
        "answer": "The profile defines the level of access a user can have in Salesforce.\nIn Salesforce org, it is possible to assign a single profile to any number of users. For example, we can consider a sales or service team in a company. The entire team has access to the same profile. The admin can create one profile for the whole sales team, which will have access to the leads, campaigns, contacts, and other objects deemed necessary by the company.\nIn this functionality, many users can be assigned with the same profile. In case the team leader needs access to additional records, then it can be done by assigning permission sets only for those users.\nEach user can be assigned only one profile.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "com?",
        "answer": "Salesforce.com is a software as a service (SaaS), and Force.com is a platform as a service (PaaS).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What is the relationship in Salesforce? What are its types?",
        "answer": "We can establish a relation between objects in Salesforce. We can associate one object with others.\nExample: We have an object party (To store information about the party), and you want to associate it with other objects like people (information of participants) so that you can associate the object party with people. These relationship types also determine how they handle record sharing, required field in page layouts, data deletion capability.\nSalesforce supports the following types of relationships that can be established among objects.\nMaster-Detail Relationship\nLookup relationship\nSelf-relationship\nExternal lookup relationship\nIndirect lookup relationship\nMany-to-Many relationship\nHierarchical relationship",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What is Master-detail relationship?",
        "answer": "It's a tightly coupled relationship among Salesforce objects. In the Master-detail relationship, the parent record controls the behavior of the child record regarding visibility and sharing. If a master record gets deleted, then the child records associated with it are also deleted. The security setting of the parent object applies to the child object.\nExample:\nIf we create a Master-detail relationship between the objects party and people. Where a party is a parent object, and people is a child object. Then if we delete party record, all the associated record will also get deleted.\n\nWhen two objects form a Master-detail relationship, we can create a unique type of field over the master object, called Roll-up summary.\nA Roll-up summary allows us to calculate values related to child record, such as the number of child record, average, sum, etc., linked to a parent record.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What is the lookup relationship?",
        "answer": "It's a loosely coupled relationship among Salesforce objects. In the Lookup relationship, both parent and child have their sharing setting and security controls, which means if a parent record gets deleted, then child records remain in the system.\nLet's see the party and the people objects. For example, the below figure provdes a visual representation of the Lookup relationship between the party and people objects.\n\nIn this diagram, the party object record has been deleted, but the people record is still available. This relationship between objects is Lookup relationship.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What are reports in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Reports are an essential part of any business. Descriptions provide a clear picture of the management.\nReports are used to track the process towards its various tasks, control expenditure, increase revenue. Reports help in trend prediction.\nSalesforce.com allows you to generate reports in different styles.\nIn Salesforce.com, we can create four types of reports:\nTabula reports\nSummary Reports\nMatrix report\nJoined report",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What are some Governor limits in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Governor limits control how much data and how many records you can store in the shared databases because Salesforce is a multi-tenant architecture based. In other words, Salesforce uses a single database to store the data of multiple customers.\nSalesforce introduced the concept of the Governor limits to prevent monopolization of the shared resources between users.\nGovernor limits are the biggest challenge of a Salesforce developer. This is because if the apex code exceeds the limit, then the issue is a runtime exception that can't be handled. So as a Salesforce developer, you should be very careful while developing application.\nHere is a list of some significant Governor limits.\nPre-transaction Apex limits\nStatic Apex limits\nSize-Specific Apex limits\nMiscellaneous Apex limits\nForce.com Platform Apex Limits\nEmail limits\nPush Notification limits",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What are the different ways to store various types of records in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "There are many different ways in Salesforce to store various records, such as Images, files, and documents. Some of them are as follows:\nAttachment\nGoogle drive\nChatter files\nLibraries",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What is the fiscal year in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Starting and ending date of a company financial year is considered as Fiscal year. The fiscal year is used to calculate annual financial statements in business and other organizations. Salesforce has two types of the fiscal year:\nStandard Fiscal year\nCustom Fiscal year\nStandard fiscal year\nSalesforce provides a calendar by default as the standard fiscal year. It's a Gregorian calendar. But it is not necessary that all the organizations use the same calendar, some organizations use different calendars and need to change the fiscal year start month. It can be defined whether the fiscal year is based on the start or end of the selected month.\nTo set up a standard fiscal year navigate to\nSetup-> Administer->company profile-> Fiscal year  \nSelect the option of Standard Fiscal year\nCustom fiscal year\nWhen the standard fiscal year does not meet the requirements of the organization, then Custom fiscal year is used. To use the custom fiscal year, the administrator has to enable it. The administrator must define the fiscal year to fit the company's calendar.\nTo set up the company's fiscal year, navigate to\nSetup-> Administer-> company profile-> Fiscal year  \nSelect the option of Custom Fiscal year\nSelect the checkbox next to the terms statement\nClick on Enable custom fiscal year\nClick on OK",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) How many Master-detail relationship fields can be created in an object?",
        "answer": "There is a maximum of two Master-detail relationship fields possible in an object.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) How many Lookup relationship fields can be created in an object?",
        "answer": "There is a maximum of 40 Lookup relationship fields possible in an object.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What are the benefits of the Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce is the largest and leading cloud platform provider in the world. Their customer relationship manager (CRM) is one of the most beneficial software.\nADVERTISEMENT\nWe get the following benefits by using CRM\nImproved understanding of the organization\nEnhanced communication b/w client and service provider\nWe can facilitate the customer better by understanding them.\nSalesforce automates the repeated tasks.\nSalesforce reduces cost and cycle time.\nSalesforce improves the efficiency of teams.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What is a sandbox org? What are the different types of sandboxes in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "A sandbox is a copy of the production org/environment. It is used for testing and development purpose. It is beneficial because it allows for the development of Apex programming without disturbing the production environment.\nSandbox can be used when we want to test a newly developed force.com application. We can develop and test it in the sandbox org, there is no need to do it directly in production.\nThere are four types of sandboxes are in Salesforce.com:\nDeveloper\nDeveloper Pro\nPartial Copy\nFull",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What is Apex in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Apex is a strongly typed object-oriented programming language. It allows developers to execute flow and transaction control statements on Salesforce server in combination with calls to the API. Its syntax looks like Java. It uses syntax and acts as a database stored procedure. Apex allows the developer to add business logic to system events like button clicks, related record update, and Visualforce pages.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What is Visualforce?",
        "answer": "Visualforce is a framework for the Force.com platform. It is a component based markup language. It allows defining user interface component in Salesforce. Page layout feature will enable you to configure the user interface easily, but by using Visualforce pages, you can customize your user interface.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) Can you edit an apex trigger/ apex class in a production environment? Can you edit a Visualforce page in a production environment?",
        "answer": "No, we can't edit apex classes and triggers directly in the production environment.\nTo edit an apex trigger/ class, first, it needs to be done in Developer edition or testing org or Sandbox org. Then, we can deploy it in production. A user that has apex permission must deploy the triggers and classes using deployment tools.\nThough, Visualforce page can be created and edited in both production and sandbox.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) Why are Visualforce pages served from a different domain?",
        "answer": "Visualforce pages are served from a different domain to block cross-site scripting and improve security standard.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) What are the static and dynamic dashboards? Can dynamic dashboards be scheduled?",
        "answer": "Static dashboards are the ordinary dashboards that will be visible to any other user who has made a report out of his data. Example; sales managers/ marketing manager would be able to see on his Salesforce Org. Moreover, a normal dashboard that shows the data for a single user.\nDynamic dashboards display information which is customized for a specific user. Let's consider the above example. In case the sales manager wants to view the report of a particular team member, then he can use dynamic dashboards.\nWe can use dynamic dashboards when we want to show user-specific data such as a particular user's quota, sales, productivity, meetings, etc.\nWe can use a normal/ static dashboard to show regional and organization-wide data to a set of users, such as sale in a region, or team performance, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) Which fields are automatically indexed in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Following fields are automatically indexed in Salesforce:\nPrimary keys (id, name and owner fields)\nForeign keys (master-detail or lookup fields)\nAudit keys (Such as SystemModStamp)\nCustom fields ( These fields Patent as an External ID or a unique area)",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What are skinny tables?",
        "answer": "Salesforce can create skinny tables to avoid join and contain frequently used fields. Thin tables improve the performance of read-only operations. Skinny tables are set aside in sync with their source tables when the source table is modified.\nContact Salesforce customer support to use skinny tables. These tables are created and used automatically where appropriate. We can't create, modify, or thin access tables.\nConsiderations for skinny tables\nADVERTISEMENT\nIt can contain a maximum of 100 columns.\nTables cannot contain fields from other objects.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) What is an Audit trail in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "The Audit trail tracks the recent setup changes that other administrators and you have made to your organization. This is useful for organizations that have more than one administrator.\nIt can track the last twenty changes made to your organization. It displays\nThe date and time of the change.\nWho made it (administrator name)\nWhat was before the change",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) Can we delete a user in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "No, it is not possible to delete the user in the salesforce.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) Can we change the license when we create a profile?",
        "answer": "No, we cannot change the license after creating the profile.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) What is Deployment in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "In SFDC (Salesforce development cycle), you have to develop code in Sandbox, and then you might need to deploy this to another sandbox or production environment this is called deployment.\nIn other words, the movement of metadata from one organization to another organization is called deployment. The main reason behind deployment is that you cannot develop apex in your Salesforce production.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) What are the different ways of deployment in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Deployment can be done in the following ways.\nChange Sets\nEclipse with Force.com IDE\nForce.com Migration Tool - ANT/Java based\nSalesforce Package",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What is the difference between a standard controller and a custom controller?",
        "answer": "The standard controller automatically contains all the standard object properties and standard button functionality. It contains all the functionalities and logic as used in standard Salesforce pages.\nCustom controllers are like an Apex class that implements all the logic of a page without taking an advantage of a standard controller. Custom controllers are related with Visualforce page through the controller attribute.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) What is cloud computing?",
        "answer": "Cloud computing is the provision of computational services such as storage, servers, database, software, networking, analytics, intelligence, and moreover the internet (cloud). It brings the organization faster innovation, flexibility in allocating resources, economies of scale. It reduces the costs of organizations that are associated with the task of storage.\nCloud-based storage makes it possible to save the files in a remote database instead of proprietary hard drive or local storage device. It provides access to the data and the software programs to run it till an electronic accessory has access to the web.\nCloud services can be both private and public. Private cloud services provide services to a certain number of people. On the other hand, public cloud services offer their services over the internet which is chargeable. These services are a group of networks that supply hosted services. Cloud services also provide a hybrid option, which combines both private and public services.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) What are the types of Cloud services?",
        "answer": "Based on services, cloud services provide users with a series of functionalities like\nEmail\nBackup, Storage, and data retrieval\nCreating and testing app\nData Analyzing\nAudio and Video streaming\nCloud computing is still a new service, but it comes in a trend in a very short time. Nowadays, government agencies, small businesses, non-profit agencies, and individual consumers are using cloud computing.\nCloud computing is not a single part of technology like a microchip. It's a primary combination of three services software as a service (SaaS), infrastructure as a service (IaaS), and platform as a service (PaaS)",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) How many certifications are available in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "There are eight kinds of certifications available in Salesforce which cater to different stages:\nAdministrator certifications\nDeveloper Certifications\nArchitects Certifications\nApp Builders Certifications\nImplementation Experts or Consultant Certification.\nMarketers Certification\nPardot Experts Certifications\nCPQ Certification",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "34) What is Salesforce environment?",
        "answer": "Environment or organization is the workspace for a particular user.\nFor Example, if you sign up to a Facebook account, you will be provided a unique username and password. The same approach, if you subscribe to the Force.com cloud computing, you will be provided a valid credential to work in your specified cloud computing area of the environment or Org.\nThe Salesforce environment provides accessibility to develop, test the apps, and can be used for production also. This environment can be customized according to your requirements such as Apex code, workflow, Custom DB attributes, and objects.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) How to check for user License in Salesforce work environment?",
        "answer": "To check the Salesforce license, open the SF workspace and navigate as follows:\nSetup-> Monitor->System Overview  \nAnd go to Data Storage section, here you can see the user license in the highlighted area.\nIf you want to check for all user licenses, then select the \"Show All\" option.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What is MVC architecture in Visualforce?",
        "answer": "MVC is a widely used architecture design pattern which divides the design component in three phases Model, View, Controller.\n\n\nIn Visualforce MVC, architecture can be implemented by using the standard as well as custom objects. Also, we can use three newly introduced Salesforce objects, pages, components, and controllers.\nThese pages work like JSP pages, give the user-friendly presentation. Each view has an associated controller. Developers can write their controller using Apex programming language or can use a standard controller. VF has some auto-generated controller to interact with databases.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) When should apex be used?",
        "answer": "Apex can be used in different scenarios, such as\nTo create Email services\nTo create web services\nTo perform complex validation over multiple objects\nTo create complex business processes that are not supported by the workflow.\nTo create custom transaction logic\nTo attach custom logic to another operation",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "38) How does Apex work?",
        "answer": "All Apex programs run on-demand exclusively on force.com platform.\nFirst, the application server compiles the apex code into an abstract set of instructions that can be understood by apex runtime interpreter.\nAfter the compilation, the compiled code is stored to metadata.\nAnd now, when the end users initiate the execution of apex by clicking the button or visual force page, the application servers retrieve the compiled instructions from the metadata and forward them to runtime interpreter before returning the result.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "39) What are the types of SOql statements in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Salesforce Object Query Language is used to perform database operations in Salesforce.com. It is similar to the select statement in the widely used Structured Query Language (SQL), but it is designed especially for Salesforce data.\nWith the use of SOql, we can create a simple but powerful query string in the following environments:\nIn the query call () of the query String parameter.\nIn apex statements\nIn Visualforce controllers and getters method\nIn the schema explorer of Force.com IDE",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "40) What could be the reason to lose data in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Few reasons to loss data in Salesforce are as follows:\nBy changing date and date-time\nBy migrating number, percent, currency from another datatype.\nBy changing from the multi-select picklist, checkbox, auto number to other types.\nBy altering the multi-select picklist from any type except picklist\nBy changing to auto number except for the text\nBy switching from text area to email, URL, phone, and text.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "41) What is Workflow?",
        "answer": "The workflow is a programmed process which is used to validate evaluation criteria and rule criteria.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "42) What is the difference between WhoID and WhatId?",
        "answer": "\"WhoID\" denotes the people like contacts or leads. Whereas \"WhatId\" denotes the objects. Let us consider LeadID, ContactID are fields of \"WhoId\" and AccountID, OpportunityID are \"WhatId\".",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "43) What is Data Skew in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "When a maximum number of child records (more than 10k) are connected to one parent record that situation is called data skew in Salesforce.\nData skew can be three types\nAccount data skew\nOwnership skew\nLookup skew",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "44) What is collection in Apex? List out all different kinds of collections supported by Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Collections in Apex are variables that are used to store multiple data records. As there is a limitation on the number of records to be retrieved per transaction, we can use the collection variable to retrieve records.\nThere are three types of collections in Salesforce.\nList\nMaps\nSets",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "45) What are static Resources?",
        "answer": "Static resources are used to upload images, zip files, jar files, Javascript and CSS files that can be referred in a visual force page. We can upload a maximum of the 250mb file using Static resources.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "46) What is the difference between Action support and Action function?",
        "answer": "To understand the difference between Action support and Action function, let's understand their functionalities:\nBoth Action support and action function are used to call a controller method via an Ajax request.\nThe difference between them is as follows:\nAction function can call a controller method from JavaScript.\nAction function provides Ajax that supports another visualforce component and then call the controller method.\nAction function cannot support Ajax to another component. But from a particular component which supports Ajax (onclick, onblur, etc.) action function can be called to the controller method.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "47) How many types of email templates can be created in Salesforce?",
        "answer": "Different types of email templates can be created In Salesforce. Some of them are listed below.\nHTML with letterhead\nEdit HTML Templates\n\nCustom HTML\nEdit HTML Templates\n\nVisualforce",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "48) How to handle comma within a field while uploading using Data Loader?",
        "answer": "If there is a comma in field content, you will have to enclose the contents within double quotation mark;\" \".",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "49) How many callouts to external service can be made in a single Apex transaction?",
        "answer": "An Apex transaction can make a maximum of 100 callouts to an HTTP request or an API call after that governor limits will restrict it.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    },
    {
        "question": "50) What is pagination in salesforce? How can we implement it in Visualforce?",
        "answer": "Pagination is a technique to display a large number of records and displaying the records on multiple pages. We use pagination instead of controlling the number of records displayed on each page.\nBy default, a list controller shows 20 pages in a page. To customize it, we use a controller extension to set the Page Size.\nTake a look at the below sample code:\n<apex:page standardController=\"Salary\" recordSetVar=\"Salaries\">  \n<apex:pageBlock title=\"Viewing Salaries\">  \n<apex:form id=\"theForm\">  \n<apex:pageBlockSection >  \n<apex:dataList var=\"opp\" value=\"{!Salaries }\">  \n{!opp.Name}  \n</apex:dataList>  \n</apex:pageBlockSection>  \n<apex:panelGrid columns=\"4\">  \n<apex:commandLink action=\"{!first}\">FIRST</apex:commandLink>  \n<apex:commandLink action=\"{!next}\">NEXT</apex:commandLink>  \n<apex:commandLink action=\"{!previous}\">PREVIOUS</apex:commandLink>  \n<apex:commandLink action=\"{!last}\">LAST</apex:commandLink>  \n</apex:panelGrid>  \n   </apex:form>  \n</apex:pageBlock>  \n</apex:page>",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "salesforce"
    }
]